HAITHAM ENNASR

h.ennasr@gmail.com +1(917)533-2880

UX / UI and Game Designer and Developer with over eight years of user experience and interface design work over a multitude of platforms. Some works to date includes VR experiences for advertising agencies and art exhibitions, educational games, web games, and responsive websites

DESIGN SKILLS

Iterative prototyping, game design, interactive narrative design, user testing & playtesting, templates and wireframes, usermaps, brainstorming, mockups.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Unity (C#, VR, Mobile, and Desktop). HTML5 & Sass/CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Github, Processing, Arduino.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Buck Design, Unity Artist and Developer, New York	2018
Supported a team of 3d modelers, animators, designers, and programmers to build prototypes,	
assets and interactive graphic effects.	
Tribeca Film Institute, Mentor at the Interactive Co-Lab on Migration, New York	2017
Indiecade Festival, Jury Chair, Curatorial Committee,	2017
Played & reviewed independent games to select, nominate, and award recipients for the Indiecade Festival.	
CRG Gallery, UX Designer and Web Developer.	2016 - 2017.
Designed UX / UI and developed a responsive website for CRG Gallery.	
Palestine Festival of Literature, UX Designer and Web Developer.	2016 - Current.
Designed UX / UI and Developed a responsive website for the Palestinian Festival of Literature.	
Parsons School for Design, The New School, Adjunct professor	2016
Game Design, Design and Technology MFA program. New York	
CDM NY, Bespoke Unity and Web Developer, New York	2016
Playmatics, UX/UI / Game Designer and Developer	2014 - 2015
Responsibilities included UX/UI design, programming, animation, and art direction for a Unity project.	
NBC Universal, Game Designer and Developer, New York	2012 - 2013
Designed & developed games and live-content for cable television websites, such as USA network,	
Bravo, and Oxygen. With a focus on casual FTP web games, gamification, and games for digital marketing.	
Al Jazeera, Assistant Producer, Washington DC	2009 - 2010
Produced and edited television content that reached the homes of tens of millions of viewers	
internationally, responsibilities included video editing, research, and translation.	
Independent Game Designer and New Media Artist.	2010 - Current
I am an internationally exhibiting artist working in a wide range of digital and interactive media	

EDUCATION AND RESEARCH

Parsons School for Design, The New School, Masters of Fine Arts in Design and Technology. New York, 2012

Arab American University of Jenin, Bachelors of Science in Computer Information Technology. Jenin, 2008

Ashkal Alwan, Fellow at Home Workspace Program. Beirut, 2014-2015

PETLab, Parsons school for design, The New School, Research assistant. New York, 2010 - 2011

Including a VR game exhibited at Sursock Museum, Beirut in 2017. Other works were exhibited at

Daegu Art Factory, Daegu; Alternative Space Loop, Seoul; Ashkal Alwan, Beirut; Whitebox Art Center, New York; Museum of the Moving Image, New York.